Guide to the Diane Ackerman papers, 1971-1997.
Ackerman, Diane papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Diane Ackerman Papers, 1971-1997
6299
Diane Ackerman
9.1 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, galleys, proofs, reproductions of published and unpublished writings, photographs, poems, articles, essays, research notes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, galleys, proofs, and reproductions of published and unpublished writings, including The Planets, A Natural History of the Senses, A Natural History of Love, and A Slender Thread; also, photographs, poems, articles and essays, research notes, and other papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Diane Ackerman was born in Waukegan, Illinois in 1948. Her formal education, a B.A. in English from Pennsylvania State University (1970), an M.F.A. (1973), M.A. in English (1976), and Ph.D. in English (1978), all from Cornell University, coincided with her emergence as a lyric poet whose sensibilities are reminiscent of Thoreau, Whitman, and A.R. Ammons, among others. During the late 1970s and 1980s, Ackerman published three volumes of poetry and a verse drama, all with William Morrow. Ackerman gained recognition for her for creative non-fiction with the publication of A Natural History of the Senses in 1990, a work which combines keen observation and research with autobiographical insight. In A Natural History of Love (1994), and, most recently, A Slender Thread (1997), Ackerman continues her meditative exploration of the interconnection between the natural and human worlds. She has extended her readership with the publication of two non-fiction books for children: Monk Seal Hideaway (1995) and Bats: Shadows in the Night (1997). Her poetry appears in numerous anthologies and her prose is commissioned by a variety of magazines including National Geographic, New Woman, The New Yorker, and Victoria.
Ackerman lives in Ithaca, NY with her husband, novelist Paul West.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Diane Ackerman collection consists of manuscripts, galley proofs, and reproductions of her published and unpublished writings, which include nature books, novels, poetry, essays, and articles. The collection includes research materials and notes, photographs, photocopies, press badges, and other printed material. Chief among her books are: The Planets, Wife of Light, Twilight of the Tenderfoot, Lady Faustus, On Extended Wings, Reverse Thunder, A Natural History of the Senses, Jaguar of Sweet Laughter, The Moon by Whale Light, A Natural History of Love, Monk Seal Hideaway, The Rarest of the Rare, and A Slender Thread. Articles and essays in the collection include "Bats," "Crocodilians," "Penguins," "Whales," "Albatrosses," "Golden Monkeys," "Insect Love," "Last Refuge of the Monk Seals," "We Are Listening," "Sympathetic Magic," "How to Watch the Sky," "The Natural History of a Leaf," "Where the Sun Dines," and "The Children of Interplast"; and a play "Reverse Thunder."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ackerman, Diane.; Ackerman, Diane.--Planets.; Ackerman, Diane.--A Natural history of the senses.; Ackerman, Diane.--A Natural history of love.; Ackerman, Diane.--A slender thread.; Ackerman, Diane.--I praise my destroyer.
Subjects:
Authors, American.; Nature in literature.; Nature--Religious aspects.; Culture.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Published Books
The Planets: A Cosmic Pastoral (1976)
Boxes 1, 10, Mapcase
Wife of Light (1976)
Boxes 1, 2
Twilight of the Tenderfoot: A Western Memoir (1980)
Box 2
Lady Faustus (1983)
Box 2
On Extended Wings (1985)
Box 2
Reverse Thunder (1988)
Box 2
A Natural History of the Senses (1990)
Boxes 2-4
Jaguar of Sweet Laughter (1991)
Box 4
The Moon by Whale Light (1994)
Boxes 4, 5
A Natural History of Love (1994)
Boxes 5, 6
Monk Seal Hideaway (1995)
Boxes 6, 10
The Rarest of the Rare (1995)
Boxes 6, 10
A Slender Thread (1996)
Boxes 6, 7, 10, Mapcase
Bats: Shadows in the Night (1997)
Box 10
I Praise My Destroyer (1997)
Box 11
Series II. Published Articles
"Bats," New Yorker, Feb. 29, 1988
Boxes 7, 10
"Crocodilians," New Yorker, Oct. 10, 1988
Boxes 7, 8, 10
"Penguins," New Yorker, July 10, 1989
Boxes 8, 10
"Whales," New Yorker, Feb. 26, 1990
Boxes 8, 10
"Albatrosses," New Yorker, Sept. 24, 1990
Box 8
"Golden Monkeys," New Yorker, June 24, 1991
Box 8
"Insect Love," New Yorker, Aug. 17, 1992
Box 8
"Rodney Marsh" (publication unknown)
Box 8
"Last Refuge of the Monk Seals," National Geographic
Box 8
"In Praise of Squirrels," National Geographic, Nov. 1995
Box 8
"The Natural History of a Leaf," Condé Nast's Traveler, May 1988
Box 8
Essay: "How to Watch the Sky," Parade Magazine, Feb. 18, 1990
Box 8
Essay: "Where the Sun Dines" (Amazon Rain Forest), Travel-Holiday, March 1990
Box 8
"The Children of Interplast," New York Times Magazine, Oct. 20, 1991
Box 9
Series III. Unpublished Manuscripts
"Senses of Animals"
Box 8
Novel: "Sympathetic Magic"
Box 9
Series IV. Publicity
Box 9, Mapcase
Series V. Reseach Materials
Box 9
Series VI. Personal
Box 9
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Published Books
  - The Planets: A Cosmic Pastoral, New York, William Morrow & Company, 1976
    - Ms. worksheets - Jupiter (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ms. worksheets - Earth (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ms. worksheets - Mercury (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ms. worksheets - Mars (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ms. worksheets - Asteroids, Prologue (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ms. worksheets - Pluto (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ms. worksheets - Saturn (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ms. worksheets - Neptune, misc. notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ms. worksheets - Uranus (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ms. worksheets - Venus (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript - Setting copy, to p. 69, note from publisher, June 24, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript - Setting copy pp. 70-124, page entitled "for Carl Sagan" (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Galleys - 1976, unmarked (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Manuscript - Handwritten corrections, note from publisher, n.d., copyright page proof (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Manuscript - Xerox Page proofs: galley markings, xerox page proofs with handwritten corrections (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Page proofs - Master pages: pp. 1-80 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Page proofs - Master pages: pp. 81-160 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Page proofs - Author's set, notes: pp. 1-80 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Page proofs - Author's set, notes: pp. 81-160 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Photo proof sheets - Illustrated: cover-p. 30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Photo proof sheets - Illustrated: pp. 31-60 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Photo proof sheets - Illustrated: pp. 61-89 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Photo proof sheets - Illustrated: pp. 90-119 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Photo proof sheets - Illustrated: pp. 120-140 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Photo proof sheets - Illustrated: pp. 141-160 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Blues: pp. 1-160 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Illustrations - Layout worksheets, photographs (folder marked 3-26-76) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Book jacket - Layout worksheet (Folder O/S)
  - Wife of Light New York, William Morrow & Company, 1976
    - Typescript - Editorial notes, Oct. 17, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Page proofs - Galleys (author's set) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Page proofs - Galleys (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Page proofs - Marked (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Page proofs - Unmarked (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Proof - incomplete: pp. 20-64 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Twilight of the Tenderfoot: A Western Memoir, New York, William Morrow & Company, 1980
    - Worksheets - Pasted ts., some galley proofs included, 4 handwritten pages on yellow paper (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Worksheets - Typescript with handwritten corrections, 2 handwritten pages on yellow legal paper (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: preface-p. 71 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: pp. 72-145 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: pp. 146-218 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: pp. 219-289 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: preface-p. 46 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: pp. 47-99 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: pp. 100-151 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections: pp. 152-199 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Galleys - title page-p. 36, publisher's note (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Galleys - pp. 37-68, publicity sheet from Morrow, April 15, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dead matter - handwritten and typed pages, miscellaneous clippings and notes, 82 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Folio, book jacket - pp. 1-222, book jacket (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lady Faustus, New York, William Morrow & Company, 1983
    - Working manuscript, ts. and handwritten pages (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Proof - Galleys (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Folio - 94 pp. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Advance proof, publicity leaflet - 2 copies of bound advance proof, part of leaflet, (poem): "Ice Dragons in Central Park West" (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - On Extended Wings, New York, Atheneum, 1985
    - Draft of chapter "Down From Nowhere Nothing's Wax-Like Blooms," ts. with handwritten corrections, pp. 295-301, 1-294 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Manuscript - 7 preliminary pages, pp. 1-79 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Manuscript - Typescript: pp. 80-154, 2 pages of titles (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Manuscript - Typescript: pp. 155-255 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Manuscript - Typescript: pp. 256-329, "about the author" page (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout, photocopy: cover-p. 111 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout, photocopy: pp. 112-219 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout, photocopy: pp. 220-back cover (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Page proofs - Photocopy, author's set: beginning-p. 101 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Page proofs - Photocopy, author's set: pp. 102-211 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Page proofs - Photocopy, author's set: pp. 212-308 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous - Loose pages, 18 pp., letter from Atheneum Publishers, May 31, 1985, post card "Trucking Through the Turks: A Sky Art Event, Dec. 23-31, 1982" (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Reverse Thunder, New York, Lumen, 1988
    - Manuscript - Typescript, photocopy: pp. 1-38 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Manuscript - Typescript, photocopy: pp. 39-76 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - A Natural History of the Senses, New York, Random House, 1990
    - Drafts of chapters - Computer printouts with handwritten corrections, "Smell": 74 pages (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Drafts of chapters - "Smell" pp 26-35, 26-31, miscellaneous notes on "Smell" (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Drafts of chapters - Computer printouts with handwritten corrections, "Touch," July 16, 1988: 66 pages (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Drafts of chapters - Computer printouts with handwritten corrections, "Taste," Sept. 13, 1988: 60 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, photocopy: 6 preliminary pages, beginning-p. 83 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, photocopy: pp. 85-187 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, photocopy: pp. 188-289 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, photocopy: pp. 290-381, 3 pages notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout with copy editor's notes, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: 12 preliminary pages, pp. 1-84 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout with copy editor's notes, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: pp. 85-187 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout with copy editor's notes, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: pp. 188-269 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout with copy editor's notes, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: pp. 270-389 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Galleys - Master, 1st pass, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: 25 preliminary pages, pp. 1-63 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Galleys - Master, 1st pass, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: pp. 64-145 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Galleys - Master, 1st pass, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: pp. 146-227 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Galleys - Master, 1st pass, photocopy, Jan. 23, 1990: pp. 228-317 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Galleys - Master, 2nd pass, photocopy, Mar. 12, 1990: 19 preliminary pages, pp. 1-57 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Galleys - Master, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 12, 1990: pp. 58-145 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Galleys - Master, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 12, 1990: pp. 146-221 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Galleys - Master, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 12, 1990: pp. 222-317 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Index - typsetting copy, computer printout with copy editor's notes, 56p. April 16, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous corrections - Dec. 1989-April 1990; ca. 75 pages (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous corrections - Dec. 1989-April 1990; ca. 75 pages (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Repro - April 27, 1990, 22 preliminary pages; pp. 1-73 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Repro - April 27, 1990; pp. 74-172 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Repro - April 27, 1990, 22; pp. 173-248 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Repro - April 27, 1990, 22; pp. 249-332 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Blues, May 16, 1990 - 19 preliminary pages, pp. 1-12, transmittal form, Random House note, "Book Club and Trade" blues; 19 preliminary pages, pp. 1-108 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Blues, May 16, 1990 - "Book Club and Trade" blues, pp. 109-332 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Folio - 19 preliminary pages, pp. 1-140 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Folio - pp. 141-332 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Notes - Transcripts of interviews (computer printout) Odor interviews: George Preti, pp. 1-9; Chuck Wysocki, pp. 9-26; Gary Beauchamp, pp. 26-40; Beverly Coward, pp. 40-49; Richard Mattes, pp. 49-59; Anne Belcher, pp. 59-69; Michael DiNovi, pp. 69-74; notes on "The Romantic Story of Scent," John Trueman, 1975; 5 pages handwritten notes on "Algonquin" stationery; interview with Sophia Grojsman, 1988, 10 pages (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Book jackets - one in Dutch, one in English (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Titles - 2 pages of titles under consideration for A Natural History of the Senses: one handwritten page, one typed page with notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Advertisement for A Natural History of the Senses, Le Monde, July 9-10, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Publicity poster: Stand-up display for A Natural History of the Senses (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Jaguar of Sweet Laughter: New and Selected Poems, New York, Random House, 1991
    - Drafts of poems, "Air Show in Barbados," ts. - 3 pp., ts. with handwritten corrections - 3 pp., and ts. with handwritten corrections - 7 pp., ts. with handwritten corrections - 2 pp. ) (earlier titles: "An F-15 Pilot Puts on an Air Show in Barbados," "An F-15 Pilot in Barbados,""Air Show in Barbados,") "At Walt Whitman's Birthplace, Huntington, Long Island": ts. - 2 pp., 2 handwritten drafts - 2 pp., 1 p., 2 ts. drafts - 2 pp. each "Autumn Laps," 3 tss. - two - 2 pp., one - 1 p. "Because the gods are baking winter cakes.. .," one p. handwritten "Each morning a lady cardinal.. .," one handwritten p. "The Enabler," tss. - three drafts - 3 pp. each, three drafts - four pp. each, one handwritten p. (earlier titles "The Auroras of Autumn" and "The Trade Routes of Autumn") "French Frigate Shoals," four tss. - 2 pp. each, one ts. one p., handwritten notes - 4 pp. (earlier titles "Tern Island Station, French Frigate Shoals) "Halley's Comet," one 3 p. ts., five drafts, ts. with handwritten corrections, 1 p. each, one ts. with handwritten corrections - 2 pp., one handwritten p. "Halley's Comet Replies," ts. - 1 p. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Drafts of poems, "Intensive Care," one ts. - 3 pp., one ts. with handwritten corrections - 2 pp. "Kismet," fifteen tss. - 1 p., one ts. - 2 pp., one ts. - 3 pp. "Oasis," four tss., some with handwritten corrections, two - 2 pp. each, two - 3 pp. each, one - 1 p. "A Pilot's Pay," one ts. - 1 p., four tss. with handwritten corrections - 1 p. each "Portrait Without Pose," ts. - 5 pp., two tss. with handwritten corrections - 2 pp., ts. with handwritten corrections - 3 pp. "Remodeling," ts. - 3 pp., ts. with handwritten corrections, two tss. with handwritten corrections - 2 pp. each, two tss. with handwritten corrections - 3 pp. each, 1 ts. p. "We Are Listening," one ts. - 1 p., one ts. draft - 1 p., one handwritten draft - 5 pp. "White Flag," ts. - 2 pp., handwritten draft - 3 pp., ts. draft with handwritten corrections - 4 pp. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Sept. 19, 1990: 13 loose pages, 14 preliminary pages, pp. 10-54 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Sept. 19, 1990: pp. 55-117 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Sept. 19, 1990: pp. 118-182 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Oct. 26, 1990: 11 loose pages, 18 preliminary pages, pp. 1-72 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Oct. 26, 1990: pp. 73-152 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Oct. 26, 1990: pp. 153-256, "about the author" (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, Dec. 19, 1990: 16 preliminary pages, pp. 1-81 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, Dec. 19, 1990: pp. 82-169 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, Dec. 19, 1990: pp. 170-254, "about the author" (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Proof, book jacket, poem, Uncorrected advance proof, bound, 240 pages; book jacket; binding sheet; "We Are Listening" (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Moon by Whale Light: and Other Animal Adventures Among Bats, Crocodilians, Whales, and Penguins, New York, Random House, 1994
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections: 8 preliminary pages, pp. 1-71 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections: pp. 72-156 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections: pp. 157-228 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections: pp. 229-317, "about the author" (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1991: 24 preliminary pages, pp. 1-52 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1991: pp. 53-112 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1991: pp. 113-176 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1991: pp. 177-240, "about the author" (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, August 12, 1991: 24 preliminary page, pp. 1-59 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, August 12, 1991: pp. 60-143 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, August 12, 1991: pp. 144-240, index marker, "about the author" (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Repro - Aug. 12, 1991: 6 loose pages, 22 preliminary pages, pp. 1-59 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Repro - Aug. 12, 1991: pp. 60-157 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Repro - Aug. 12, 1991: pp. 158-240, indexing information, "about the author," "about this type" (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Index - Setting copy, computer printout with copy editor's notes, 34 pages, Aug. 30, 1991; page proofs, photocopy, pp. 242-246, 249, Aug. 30, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Design manuscript - Includes note from publisher, composition specifications, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1991: 4 loose pages, 22 preliminary pages, pp. 1-51 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Design manuscript - Includes note from publisher, composition specifications, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1991: pp. 52-134 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Design manuscript - Includes note from publisher, composition specifications, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1991: pp. 135-232 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Design manuscript - Includes note from publisher, composition specifications, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1991: pp. 233-317 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous - Publisher's note, title page and index, loose blues, pp. 241-249, Sept. 1, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Folio - Arcata Graphics note, inside cover-p. 90, Sept. 23, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Folio - pp. 91-250 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Dead matter - Dead camera copy, pp. 241-249, Oct. 5, 1991; dead matter, 11 pages, Nov. 4, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Uncorrected advance proof, 240 pages, book jacket (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - A Natural History of Love, New York, Random House, 1994
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: 10 preliminary pages, pp. 1-59 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 60-136 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 137-210 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 211-288 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 289-372 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 373-457 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 458-499 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Typesetting copy - Computer printout: pp. 500-563 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: printing specifications - 2 pages, 23 preliminary pages, pp. 1-55 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: pp. 56-132 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: pp. 133-185 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: pp. 186-251 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: pp. 252-304 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: pp. 305-352, "about the type" (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Galleys - Master set, 1st pass, photocopy, Feb. 9, 1994: pp. 305-352, "about the type" (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 15, 1994: pp. 50-130 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 15, 1994: pp. 131-223 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 15, 1994: pp. 224-293 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Galleys - Master set, 2nd pass, photocopy, March 15, 1994: pp. 294-346, "about the author" (p. 361), "about the type" (p. 362) (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Repro - March 22, 1994: 24 preliminary pages, pp. 1-68 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Repro - March 22, 1994: pp. 69-176 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Repro - March 22, 1994: pp. 177-266 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Repro dupe - March 22, 1994: 12 preliminary pages, pp. 1-95 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Repro dupe - March 22, 1994: pp. 96-170 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Repro dupe - March 22, 1994: pp. 171-257 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Repro dupe - March 22, 1994: pp. 258-337, "about the author" (p. 359), "about the type" (p. 360) (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Index - Setting copy, computer printout with copy editor's notes, April 18, 1994, floppy disk, galleys, photocopy, pp. 345-358 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Manuscript - Computer printouts, photocopies, annotated: "Annie's Copy" (Anne Druyan Sagan), cover-p. 170 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript - Computer printouts, photocopies, annotated: "Annie's Copy," pp. 171-315 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript - Computer printouts, photocopies, annotated: "Annie's Copy," pp. 316-back cover (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript - Computer printouts, photocopies, annotated: "Meredith's Copy" (Meredith Small), cover-p. 170 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript - Computer printouts, photocopies, annotated: "Meredith's Copy," pp. 171-315 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript - Computer printouts, photocopies, annotated: "Meredith's Copy," p. 316-back cover (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dead matter/loose notes - ca. 80 pages in each folder (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
    - Advance Uncorrected Proof, bound, 350 pages (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Monk Seal Hideaway, New York, Crown, 1995